<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Wander</title><subtitle>A place where Richard records personal thoughts and discuss them with friends.</subtitle> <updated>2021-10-03T13:14:09-04:00</updated> <author> <name>Richard Xu</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Richard Xu </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Writings Coming Up!</title><link href="/posts/next-issues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writings Coming Up!" /><published>2021-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2021-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/next-issues/</id> <content src="/posts/next-issues/" /> <author> <name>Richard Xu</name> </author> <category term="Harvard" /> <summary> tl;dr: New writings about academics, coming out every Tuesday / Thursday / Saturday, until I don’t have interesting things to talk about. I have not been writing enough in the past few semesters. Perhaps this is because I was busy, or because I didn’t value writing at the time. Nevertheless, I have not written reflections on the work I do for a while now. As I start my senior fall, I am begin... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Recommendations for Applying to Tech/Finance Internships</title><link href="/posts/tech-internship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recommendations for Applying to Tech/Finance Internships" /><published>2021-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2021-10-03T13:09:34-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/tech-internship/</id> <content src="/posts/tech-internship/" /> <author> <name>Richard Xu</name> </author> <category term="Harvard" /> <summary> A friend who’s going into sophomore year asked me about applying to tech internships. As someone who has gone through the process a few times, I thought it would be helpful to write down my thoughts. I will use “tech” to describe anything that attracts Math/CS students, which often includes finance as well. Recruiting Timeline Since many companies are recruiting for strong talents, we get a “r... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Tech Setup</title><link href="/posts/tech-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Setup" /><published>2021-05-30T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2021-05-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/tech-setup/</id> <content src="/posts/tech-setup/" /> <author> <name>Richard Xu</name> </author> <category term="Random" /> <summary> This is a super chill post! My old laptop was getting quite old and I recently got a new one. During installation I had some time to reflect on the tech choices / apps I use. My setup is quite minimal, and I thought I would share the tools in case anyone find this useful. Overall Setup I use a Macbook running Windows on Bootcamp. As a Windows user since 2003, I love it. However, I have always ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Personal opinions on Harvard courses</title><link href="/posts/harvard-classes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Personal opinions on Harvard courses" /><published>2021-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2021-05-27T18:50:06-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/harvard-classes/</id> <content src="/posts/harvard-classes/" /> <author> <name>Richard Xu</name> </author> <category term="Harvard" /> <summary> I took many classes in my first 3 semester of Harvard. While on a walk, I started to think about what I learned from each class. Furthermore, a few students have asked me about course recommendations. So, I thought this is a good time to write down what I thought about each class I took. This is not a perscriptive formula. Instead, it is a single data point from a person who is as lost as you ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Why do we Overpack our Schedules?</title><link href="/posts/why-busy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do we Overpack our Schedules?" /><published>2021-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</published> <updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/why-busy/</id> <content src="/posts/why-busy/" /> <author> <name>Richard Xu</name> </author> <category term="Harvard" /> <summary> During the semester, I tried to meet up and call my friends from school. However, finding a good time to do so is often difficult as people have classes and meetings during most awake hours. Then, when I call, it seems that we are always swamped by work. I am also guilty of packing my schedule so tight that I can’t find time for my friends or for exploring something new. However, overpacked sch... </summary> </entry> </feed>
